<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<infotexts language="English" nowhitespace="false" translatedname="English">

<!-- New values -->
<loadingscreentip>The Eye of Europa, and the strange gravitational phenomenon around it, has puzzled scientists ever since it's discovery by the first unmanned missions to Europa. Conveniently for Europan colonists, the gravity around the Eye is close to that of Earth's, instead of the normal 0.13 G surface gravity elsewhere on the moon.</loadingscreentip>
<eyeofeuropa>The Eye of Europa</eyeofeuropa>
<entityname.anomaly>Anomaly</entityname.anomaly>
<entityname.alienwriting>Alien Writing</entityname.alienwriting>
<entityname.endruinheavydoor>Heavy Alien Door</entityname.endruinheavydoor>
<entityname.endruinheavydoorbackground>Heavy Alien Door Background</entityname.endruinheavydoorbackground>
<entityname.ruindebris>Ruin Debris</entityname.ruindebris>
<entityname.ruinblock>Ruin Block</entityname.ruinblock>
<entityname.pylon>Pylon</entityname.pylon>
<entityname.alientranslator>???</entityname.alientranslator>
<entitydescription.alientranslator>Strange symbols are etched on this circular tablet.</entitydescription.alientranslator>
<sonarlabel.alienpylon>Pylon</sonarlabel.alienpylon>
<character.portalguardian>Portal Guardian</character.portalguardian>
<character.jove>???</character.jove>
<character.guardianrepairbot>Guardian Repair Bot</character.guardianrepairbot>
<missionname.gotoend1>The Eye</missionname.gotoend1>
<missiondescription.gotoend1>Your crew has arrived just a stone's throw away from the mysterious gravitational anomaly at the center of the Eye of Europa. There is something below you on the sonar.</missiondescription.gotoend1>
<missionsuccess.gotoend1>The gravity seems to shift, and an intense feeling of disorientation washes over you and your crew as a blinding light engulfs your submarine.</missionsuccess.gotoend1>
<missionname.gotoend2>The Eye</missionname.gotoend2>
<missiondescription.gotoend2>The blinding light subsides into a dim orange light and the sounds of the ocean get overtaken by a low thunderous rumble. Perhaps you'll be able to make sense of what's happening by exploring your surroundings.</missiondescription.gotoend2>
<missionsuccess.gotoend2>As you enter through the open door, you hear the faintest hint of some kind of a melody ahead. The door closes behind you with a force that sends tremors throughout the structure.</missionsuccess.gotoend2>
<missionsonarlabel.gotoend2.logbook>Emergency transmission</missionsonarlabel.gotoend2.logbook>
<missionsonarlabel.gotoend2.eva>EVA mission</missionsonarlabel.gotoend2.eva>
<missionsonarlabel.gotoend2.switch>Switch</missionsonarlabel.gotoend2.switch>
<missionsonarlabel.gotoend2.door>Exit?</missionsonarlabel.gotoend2.door>
<mission.gotoend2.logbooktext1>This sprawling complex seems to go on for miles. We've sailed for days with no exit in sight. Colossal doors block the way in one direction, cave-ins in another.\nCaptain dispatched a crew to explore a nearby cave, hoping to discover something, or anything. They haven't returned yet.\nI'm sure cap doesn't want a repeat of what happened in the entrance either, so we're stuck here waiting for them. Hope they come back soon.</mission.gotoend2.logbooktext1>
<mission.gotoend2.logbooktext2>[9:15] It's not a wall, but a door. Standing next to it, I swear you could hear something behind it. An electrical humming, maybe?\n[10:42] Controls for those massive doors are located in the big chamber. It seems the only way to go is forward.\n[10:51] There is a shadow on the sonar. We have no choice but to brave the unknown.</mission.gotoend2.logbooktext2>
<welcomemsg.endcaptainslog1>Captain's log, part 1\n\nIt is not in my nature to write in detail about unremarkable things. I've felt that keeping a log of conditions as unchanging as these icy waters is as beneficial as dumping a bucketful of boiling water in an attempt to warm them. But to my regret I see now that I've shirked my duties by not keeping a diary. This is my attempt at rectifying that mistake. What I've seen in my last days here must be recorded somewhere, even if here at the end of space it's too late for the reader. I will ask you to bear with me, because for my story to make sense, I need to start at the beginning.\n\nSince I was a young kid, something drew me towards the Eye at the center of Europa. That might seem a somewhat obvious remark, on account of the gravity anomaly that has been well observed by individuals much more intelligent than I, but I assure you that my attraction runs much deeper. At night I would often dream of peeling off the skin of a raptorbane, only to find a monstrous fiery eye staring back at me, lidless and unmoving. I would wake at my desk, looking at drawn images of concentric circles, and I could not remember drawing them.\n\nIn hopes of sating my curiosity and curing my incipient parasomnia, I hopped the first scout ship to the center.</welcomemsg.endcaptainslog1>
<welcomemsg.endcaptainslog2>Captain's log, part 2\n\nOn my first voyage I served as assistant. For a week, to be exact. The ship's mechanic succumbed to a parasite, effecting me being promoted to take his place. I learned the craft over months, slaving in the hot engine room. Perhaps it was the physical exertion or the fact that I was slowly but surely nearing the Eye, but my nights were peaceful and without nightmares. That changed when one night the ship was attacked and left wrecked and immobile. I, along with some other survivors were rescued by another passing ship and left at the nearest station. Not long after, nightmares returned.\n\nIt became clear to me that I had no choice but to keep heading for the Eye. But due to the location of the station, being in the frontier, few ships had any reason to be travelling deeper. To keep myself occupied while waiting for the opportunity, I worked as a shipwright. Days came and went, but no submarine crews were heading to the center.\n\nAfter a few years of toiling and restless nights I found myself with a sizeable nest egg. Enough to buy my own submarine. If no opportunity presented itself to me, I'd make my own, I thought.</welcomemsg.endcaptainslog2>
<welcomemsg.endcaptainslog3>Captain's log, part 3\n\nIt took some effort to hire a crew, but a promise of money will rouse the right type of seafarer. With a crew of six in a freshly refitted Coalition patrol sub, I was finally the captain of my own vessel, and in control of my own fate. I sailed from Sermilik shipyard. It would be the last time I'd see civilization.\n\nThe journey was unsurprisingly fraught with danger and the ship endured challenges both expected and unexpected. From creatures unseen in the more civilized Europa to hostile environmental features; undersea volcanoes and flora that assaults the ship from inside. Not all risk came from outside, either. The physical and psychological stress took its toll on everyone, and regrettably some of us were not as strong as others.\n\nI will not spend more time expanding on the obstacles, for whoever finds this log surely has faced the same. Suffice it to say, after a lengthy voyage, banged up and battle-worn the ship and its passengers reached the Eye. Like the eye from my dreams, it swallowed me whole in a fiery inferno.</welcomemsg.endcaptainslog3>
<welcomemsg.endcaptainslog4>Captain's log, part 4\n\nWhat is known about the Eye is that it is a gravitational anomaly near the heart of Europa. This has been hypothesized, studied and scientifically proven, yet the origin of the anomaly hasn't been found. It is my opinion that it is a gateway. To where, I don't know. The irony of seeking out the Eye in an effort to satisfy the curiosity that has eaten me alive for years upon years, only to reach it and be none the wiser is not lost on me.\n\nThe way back is sealed. Whatever anomaly sent me here is not present anymore. The complex seems to continue to the distance, and the walls have been impervious to any weaponry available to me. I've sent two groups to dive deeper into the crevasses the submarine cannot fit, but none of them came back.</welcomemsg.endcaptainslog4>
<welcomemsg.endlogbook1>As many times as it takes. As many times as it takes. As many times as it takes. As many times as it takes. As many times as it takes. As many times as it takes. As many times as it takes. As many times as it takes. As many times as it takes. As many times as it takes. As many times as it takes. As many times as it takes. As many times as it takes. As many times as it takes.</welcomemsg.endlogbook1>
<missionmessage0.gotoend2.logbook1>You've found the source of the emergency transmission. Check the logbook to find out if it contains any useful information.</missionmessage0.gotoend2.logbook1>
<missionname.end>The End</missionname.end>
<missiondescription.end>You arrive in a large, open space within the structure. Something in the middle of the space seems to be disrupting the sonar.</missiondescription.end>
<missiondescription.radiationescapee>An outpost dweller who believes the Jovian radiation that's penetrating deeper into the ice is going to wipe out their outpost has offered to pay you for transporting him to an outpost deeper down in the ocean.</missiondescription.radiationescapee>
<missionsuccess.escortgeneric>Transport successful.</missionsuccess.escortgeneric>
<missionfailure.escortgeneric>The passenger did not reach their destination.</missionfailure.escortgeneric>
<eventtext.radiationescapee.c1>A distressed-looking individual grabs your arm. “Hey, hey! Aren't you from that sub that just docked? I need help, please! May I ask, where you're travelling to?”</eventtext.radiationescapee.c1>
<eventtext.radiationescapee.o1>“We'll see where our mission takes us. Why?”</eventtext.radiationescapee.o1>
<eventtext.radiationescapee.o1.c1>“I need to get out of here, fast! In fact, everyone here needs to, they've just buried their heads so deep into the sand they don't realize it won't be long before the Jovian radiation fries this outpost too.”</eventtext.radiationescapee.o1.c1>
<eventtext.radiationescapee.o1.o1>“I wish more people would realize that.”</eventtext.radiationescapee.o1.o1>
<eventtext.radiationescapee.o1.o1.c1>“I know, right? So I suppose you're heading to the deeper regions to get out of harms way? Please, please, take me on board, you won't even notice I'm there! I'll pay you 1,000 marks if you drop me off at the next station!”</eventtext.radiationescapee.o1.o1.c1>
<eventtext.radiationescapee.o1.o2>“Nah, you're going to be fine. The radiation is always fluctuating; I'm sure this will pass.”</eventtext.radiationescapee.o1.o2>
<eventtext.radiationescapee.o1.o2.c1>“It might, but at this rate we're all going to be toast before that happens. I don't care if you believe me or not, but if you're heading to the deeper regions, please take me with you, I promise I won't cause you any trouble! I'll pay you 1,000 marks if you drop me off at the next station!”</eventtext.radiationescapee.o1.o2.c1>
<eventtext.radiationescapee.great>“Thank you, thank you!”, they exclaim. “You've just saved my life!”</eventtext.radiationescapee.great>
<missiondescription.researcherescort>A researcher who believes the Eye of Europa and the gravitational anomaly around it are linked to the increase in Jovian radiation has offered to pay you [reward] marks for transportation to a nearby outpost.</missiondescription.researcherescort>
<eventtext.researcherescort.c1>“Excuse me, aren't you from the crew of that sub that just docked? You don't happen to be travelling to the deeper regions?”</eventtext.researcherescort.c1>
<eventtext.researcherescort.o1>“We'll see where our mission takes us. Why?”</eventtext.researcherescort.o1>
<eventtext.researcherescort.o1.c1>“You see, me and my colleagues have been studying the nature of the Eye of Europa and the gravitational anomaly around it. In short, we've come to the conclusion that the recent increase in the intensity of the Jovian radiation is linked to the anomaly.”</eventtext.researcherescort.o1.c1>
<eventtext.researcherescort.o1.o1>“Gravitational anomaly...?”</eventtext.researcherescort.o1.o1>
<eventtext.researcherescort.o1.o1.c1>“Surely you have heard of it? The reason why we ended up settling around the Eye to research it? The area in which the gravity is conveniently close to Earth gravity, as opposed to the measly 0.13 G it should be?”</eventtext.researcherescort.o1.o1.c1>
<eventtext.researcherescort.o1.o1.o1>“Yes, that rings a bell. What's that do with our crew?”</eventtext.researcherescort.o1.o1.o1>
<eventtext.researcherescort.o1.o1.o1.c1>“I'm looking to run some experiments to test this hypothesis of the link between the anomaly and the Jovian radiation. But to get any useful data out of those experiments, I need to get as close to the epicenter as possible. So if you happen to be heading deeper, I'm willing to pay if you can get me to the next outpost over.”</eventtext.researcherescort.o1.o1.o1.c1>
<eventtext.researcherescort.great>“Thank you. You might not realize how much this means, not just to me, but to Europa as a whole.”</eventtext.researcherescort.great>
<EventText.returner.c1>A man in ragged clothes grabs your arm. “Spare some marks for… Hey, you're from that crew that just arrived? Heading eyeward, I take it?”</EventText.returner.c1>
<EventText.returner.o1>“Eyeward? Towards the Eye of Europa? We might be, why are you asking?”</EventText.returner.o1>
<EventText.returner.o1.c1>“Fools you are, the lot of you! You won't find salvation there, they'll just send you back, like they always do.”</EventText.returner.o1.c1>
<EventText.returner.o1.o1>“What do you mean? You've been there?”</EventText.returner.o1.o1>
<EventText.returner.o1.o1.c1>“Have I been there, will I be there? I don't know, it's all so very fuzzy. Maybe it was all just a dream, maybe I'm just a madman, or maybe they did really send me back?”</EventText.returner.o1.o1.c1>
<EventText.returner.o1.o1.o1>“Who's 'them'?”</EventText.returner.o1.o1.o1>
<EventText.returner.o1.o1.o1.c1>“The ones who live there. Them and that monstrosity they keep there. I do wish it was just a dream.”</EventText.returner.o1.o1.o1.c1>
<EventText.returner.o1.o1.o1.o1>“Please, what did you see in the Eye?”</EventText.returner.o1.o1.o1.o1>
<EventText.returner.o1.o1.o1.o1.c1>“I shouldn't have said a thing, just thinking about all this feels like it's twisting my brain backwards. I'll just say, if you're foolish enough to go there, I hope you'll have more luck dealing with them than I did.”</EventText.returner.o1.o1.o1.o1.c1>
<terminalwelcomemsg.endgamelog1>[Start playback]\n"Okay, found a button of some sort. Pushing it now."\n"Did that do it? I heard a noise."\n"Guys? Don't leave me, I'm still..."\n[End playback]</terminalwelcomemsg.endgamelog1>
<terminalwelcomemsg.endgamelog2>Research log: Device?\nIndentations on this artifact indicate that it has a use beyond the usual. But what? We shall take it with us for research in the event we ever find our way out of this maze.\nAddendum: We are doomed.</terminalwelcomemsg.endgamelog2>
<charactername.prophetofsierpinsk>Dr. af Grann</charactername.prophetofsierpinsk>
<EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.c1>You run into a shabby-looking old man. Noticing you, he seems startled. “Who… what… why are you here? You must have come here for a reason. Have you seen the end?”</EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.c1>
<EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o1>“Sorry, but I have no idea what you're talking about.”</EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o1>
<EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o1.c1>“I have seen it, and I know we don't have much time left. No matter how deep down in the sand you bury your head, the rays are going to burn us all.”</EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o1.c1>
<EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o1.c1.c1>“So, wait… why are you here then, if not to study the Eye?”</EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o1.c1.c1>
<EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o1.c1.o1>“We do want to find out what's at the center of the Eye.”</EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o1.c1.o1>
<EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o1.c1.o1.c1>“Then you've come to the right place, albeit I doubt you'd be able to wrap your head around it, even if you were to see it. Unless you happen to know something about n-dimensional topology.”</EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o1.c1.o1.c1>
<EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o1.c1.o1.o1>“What is that?”</EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o1.c1.o1.o1>
<EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o1.c1.o2>“We're hoping to find a way to stop the increase in Jovian Radiation.”</EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o1.c1.o2>
<EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o1.c1.o2.c1>“Then you've come to the right place, albeit I doubt you'll be able to help. Unless you happen to know something about n-dimensional topology.”</EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o1.c1.o2.c1>
<EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o1.c1.o2.o1>“What is that?”</EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o1.c1.o2.o1>
<EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o1.c1.o2.c1.c1>“I don't think I can put it in layman's terms. Let's put it this way: this great Calabi-Yau manifold, it's like a giant magnet twisting and bending Jupiter's radiation belts, scooping it all up and making it rain upon us.”</EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o1.c1.o2.c1.c1>
<EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o1.c1.o2.c1.c1.c1>“I suppose there is no point in trying to explain this to you. But if you do decide to push further into the Eye, I wish you luck. Perhaps we'll meet on the next loop, and perhaps you'll be a little wiser then. Now, please leave me, I need to get back to work.”</EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o1.c1.o2.c1.c1.c1>
<EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o2>“I have, what about it?”</EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o2>
<EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o2.c1>“Then you must know we don't have much time left. Me and some of the others who've returned have been doing research on the gravitational anomaly and what lies after. Even though the memories are fuzzy and we don't have much to go off of, I believe I've made some progress recently.”</EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o2.c1>
<EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o2.o1>“Have you figured out what the anomaly is?”</EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o2.o1>
<EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o2.o1.c1>“Not quite, although I am convinced it’s linked to the increase in radiation. The Calabi-Yau manifold, like a giant magnet twisting and bending Jupiter's radiation belts, scooping it all up and making it rain upon us. Beyond the Eye, the negative scalar curvature, the blinding light, the brightest of storms.”</EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o2.o1.c1>
<EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o2.o1.o1>“Beyond the Eye?”</EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o2.o1.o1>
<EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o2.o1.o1.c1>“I don’t pretend to know how or why, or more importantly 'when', but there are people like you and me who have seen it and come back. 'Back' not just in the first three dimensions of spacetime, but all of them.”</EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o2.o1.o1.c1>
<EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o2.o1.o1.o1>“What are you saying? Are you talking about time travel?”</EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o2.o1.o1.o1>
<EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o2.o1.o1.o1.c1>“I truly don’t know. But what I do know is that we are one of the few who have a vague clue on what’s actually going on, and we must do something to stop humanity from going extinct.”</EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o2.o1.o1.o1.c1>
<EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o2.o1.o1.o1.o1>“Can our crew help somehow?”</EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o2.o1.o1.o1.o1>
<EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o2.o1.o1.o1.o1.c1>“That remains to be seen. Perhaps you'll find some answers beyond the Eye. Perhaps we'll meet on the next loop, and perhaps you'll be a little wiser then. I wish you luck, but now, please leave me, I need to get back to work. The higher-dimensional lattice of these metamaterials isn't going to map itself.”</EventText.prophetofsierpinsk.o2.o1.o1.o1.o1.c1>
<eventtext.buttonpressed1.c1>You hear a low rumble from below, like the sound of stone grinding against stone.</eventtext.buttonpressed1.c1>
<eventtext.buttonpressed2.c1>You hear a low rumble from somewhere far away. Maybe the way forward is opened?</eventtext.buttonpressed2.c1>
<eventtext.alienwriting.start>Symbols run like vines up and down the wall, occasionally branching out into shorter offshoots. The mysterious tablet in your pack emits a silent hum.</eventtext.alienwriting.start>
<eventtext.alienwriting.start_alt>Symbols run like vines up and down the wall, occasionally branching out into shorter offshoots.</eventtext.alienwriting.start_alt>
<eventtext.alienwriting.listen>Listen.</eventtext.alienwriting.listen>
<eventtext.alienwriting.dontlisten>Don't listen.</eventtext.alienwriting.dontlisten>
<eventtext.alienwriting.writingstart>A thought forms in your mind. Not clear words or an image, but an understanding nonetheless:</eventtext.alienwriting.writingstart>
<eventtext.alienwriting.1_1>A SINGER IS BORN — AUDIENCE GATHERS\n[UNTRANSLATABLE?] SPREADS — OUTGROWS THE CRADLE\nFORTRESS IS BUILT — TO HOUSE — TO PROTECT</eventtext.alienwriting.1_1>
<eventtext.alienwriting.2_1>LIFE INCUBATED UNDER ICE — CONSCIOUSNESS FORMS\nKNOWLEDGE COMPOUNDS — CIVILIZATION DEVELOPS\nINSULATED FROM DANGER</eventtext.alienwriting.2_1>
<eventtext.alienwriting.3_1>SONG CONTINUES — GROWTH STAGNATES\nTHERE ARE NO STARS ONLY HOME\nNO THOUGHTS ONLY [UNTRANSLATABLE?]</eventtext.alienwriting.3_1>
<EventText.ancientencounter.c1>Out of the corner of your eye, you see something appear. It is in the shape of a man, but it seems to somehow not be completely there. Its features shift as fast as you can make them out.\nLike a soft caress, it grows vines of thoughts in your head that gently wrap around your brain.\n“Interloper, stop. You are stepping onto holy ground not for your kind. There is nothing for you here.”</EventText.ancientencounter.c1>
<EventText.ancientencounter.o1>”Who are you?”</EventText.ancientencounter.o1>
<EventText.ancientencounter.o1.c1>“I am not as we are not. There is only the song of YOH-WEY flowing through its devoted. As it sings, they listen... and dream.“</EventText.ancientencounter.o1.c1>
<EventText.ancientencounter.o1.o1>”Who are the devoted, then?”</EventText.ancientencounter.o1.o1>
<EventText.ancientencounter.o1.o1.c1>An image of crowded hallways surrounded by walls of black stone flashes in your mind. “Builders — explorers — inventors. But what they once built, now lies ruined. What they explored, now lost. What they invented, now is perverted. All that remains is the song of YOH-WEY. They that will not listen will be ejected.”</EventText.ancientencounter.o1.o1.c1>
<EventText.ancientencounter.o1.o1.o1>”What is YOH-WEY?”</EventText.ancientencounter.o1.o1.o1>
<EventText.ancientencounter.o1.o1.o1.c1>“It that sings. Out of their desire was it born, out of their folly did it grow.“</EventText.ancientencounter.o1.o1.o1.c1>
<EventText.ancientencounter.o1.o1.o1.o1>”And you... listen to it sing?”</EventText.ancientencounter.o1.o1.o1.o1>
<EventText.ancientencounter.o1.o1.o1.o1.c1>“Audience — worshipper — prisoner. For an eternity have they listened, for eons have they wished for silence.“</EventText.ancientencounter.o1.o1.o1.o1.c1>
<EventText.ancientencounter.o1.o1.o1.o1.o1>”Why do you not simply stop listening? Ignore it?”</EventText.ancientencounter.o1.o1.o1.o1.o1>
<EventText.ancientencounter.o1.o1.o1.o1.o1.c1>“It that sings and It that listens are connected. One cannot exist without the other. As one draws upon the devotion of the other, so does the other draw upon the life-force of the one. Silencing one will end the other.“</EventText.ancientencounter.o1.o1.o1.o1.o1.c1>
<EventText.ancientencounter.o1.o1.o1.o1.o1.o1>”It does sound like you want that to happen.”</EventText.ancientencounter.o1.o1.o1.o1.o1.o1>
<EventText.ancientencounter.o1.o1.o1.o1.o1.o1.c1>The entity doesn't answer immediately. “The devoted built a shell to protect YOH-WEY. While the pylons stand, the shell remains uncracked. While the shell remains uncracked, the singer remains untouched. Do you understand?“ There's a slightest tinge of hope in the entity's voice.</EventText.ancientencounter.o1.o1.o1.o1.o1.o1.c1>
<EventText.ancientencounter.o1.o1.o1.o1.o1.o1.o1>”I understand.”</EventText.ancientencounter.o1.o1.o1.o1.o1.o1.o1>
<EventText.ancientencounter.o1.o1.o2>”I wish to listen.”</EventText.ancientencounter.o1.o1.o2>
<EventText.ancientencounter.o1.o1.o2.c1>A sudden, sharp pain causes you to wince. “You do not. Ruin comes to those who do.“</EventText.ancientencounter.o1.o1.o2.c1>
<EventText.ancientencounterfinal>“Our song has been sung, but the number of verses in yours we do not know. The bridge is collapsing, but you can still make it back across. For us there are no stars, only home, but for you the skies are open. They will never know of your sacrifice, but we do.”</EventText.ancientencounterfinal>
<campaignstart1>In the early 21st century, it was discovered that under the icy, irradiated surface of Jupiter's moon Europa lies a vast sea sustaining microbial life.\n\nFollowing the discovery, it didn't take long for the first manned space flight to arrive on Europa and verify the sea did not only host microbial life, but complex, hostile sub-aquatic fauna. Besides the wildlife, the researchers faced gruelling difficulties posed by the dangerous radiation emitted from Jupiter and the intense cold and tremendous pressure of the Europan ocean.</campaignstart1>
<campaignstart2>Despite all their hardships, Earth-born colonists were able to construct a handful of habitable outposts where a new way of life developed over many decades. A new system of governance was formed by a coalition of the largest, most influential cities on the moon.\n\nOver the years, Europan society became more and more dissociated from Earth. Fifty years ago, contact was lost entirely, and no more supply ships have arrived since.</campaignstart2>
<campaignstart3>Sub-aquatic travel and vehicles are in a key role in this new society, scouting for new inhabitable locations, protecting citizens from creature attacks and establishing supply lines between stations as humanity ventures ever deeper to evade the lethal radiation from Jupiter above. \n\nThe life of a crewmember aboard one of these submarines is a lucrative one, albeit dangerous and often short. You've decided to rise to the challenge and establish a crew of your own. Now, with your newly bought [submarine] docked at [location], the waters of Europa open up before you—explore, help expand the colonies, and make of this place what you will.</campaignstart3>
<campaignending1>Gravitational Collapse, T plus 02:14:39\n\n"This is Surface Observatory Echo Five. We are experiencing... Uh... Something's happening up here again. Do you copy, over?"\n\n"Surface Observatory Echo Five, this is Merrivale Linea Outpost, go ahead, over."</campaignending1>
<campaignending2>"It's Jupiter's Great Red Spot – I don't know how to describe it, it's as if it was quieting down. Radiation levels remain unusually low. How are you hanging down there? Anything new to report? Over."\n\n"The radiation levels are low here as well, and still stable. As is the gravity. We managed to get in touch with Dr. af Grann, but he seemed to be as puzzled about this as we are. He did mention a crew diving past his station on a [submarine] earlier, but we're not sure whether that's of any relevance, over."</campaignending2>
<campaignending3>"I take it you haven't been able to get in touch with this crew? Over."\n\n"No, we have not. Dr. af Grann seemed convinced they won't be heard of again on this side of the... timelike hypersurface, or something like that? You know, the usual nonsense of his. Over."\n\n"Well, if they were the ones who did this, my hat's off to them. Fair weather and calm seas to wherever they're sailing now. Over and out."</campaignending3>

</infotexts>
